Welcome to the in detail course on Spring, Spring Boot, JPA and Hibernate. Inside Java Ecosystem
These are the mostly used and mostly appreciated frameworks.
You can't imagine an application or an project or an interview without talking about these frameworks.
So that's why if you want to become a successful Java developer, understanding and mastering these
frameworks is very important and this course is going to help you to master these frameworks by talking
and discussing about each and every concepts that we have inside the spring and associated ecosystem
projects.
So spring, right from day one when it was introduced in 2004, it is keep on changing based upon the
developer needs.
So since it is evolving a lot based upon the developer community and the latest trends.
So from last two decades, the spring framework became very popular and it is super successful.
That's why everyone inside the Java developer community, they are using Spring as a framework inside
their web applications.
If you want to build a full stack web application or if you want to build a plain back end system,
or if you want to build microservices wherever you go, you can find at least one of the project of
Spring framework is being used inside those web applications.
So with all these reasons, it's very important to understand and master the spring framework.
So before you take a decision whether to enroll for this course or not, let me cover you,
what are all the topics and concepts that I'm going to discuss inside this course?
Like you can see here, first we are going to start this course by talking about the Spring framework
introduction.
What is spring?
How it is different from the Java Enterprise Edition framework and how spring evolved over last two
decades?
What is the release timeline of spring and what are all the different projects that we have inside the
spring ecosystem?
Once we are clear about the introduction of the spring framework, we will jump on to the spring core
concepts.
So inside the spring core concepts, we are going to discuss what is an inversion of control, what
is an dependency injection and what are the beans inside the spring framework, how to create them and
how to auto wire them based upon the concepts like inversion of control and dependency injection.
And we'll also discussing about aspect oriented programming paradigm, which is available inside the
spring framework.
And once we are clear about the spring core concepts which we are going to discuss at the starting of
this course, we will jump on to the concept of spring MVC.
So when we are discussing about the spring MVC, we'll try to understand what is an MVC pattern, how
it is going to help us in building web applications.
So once we are clear about this MVC pattern, we are going to discuss how the spring MVC adopted the
MVC pattern and what is the internal architecture of the spring MVC and how it is going to make our
lives easy in building web applications with the help of MVC Pattern.
And when we are discussing about spring MVC, we'll also talk about how to perform validations on your
UI forms,
HTML forms.
That way, the bad data entered by your end user will not come into your database.
So once we are clear about the spring MVC concept, we will straight away jump on to the Thymeleaf.
So Thymeleaf will allow us to build dynamic web applications by integrating both Thymeleaf and spring
projects like Spring MVC, Spring Core and Spring Security.
So by adopting both Spring framework and Thymeleaf libraries, we are going to build a dynamic web application
inside this course, and I'll be showing a sample glimpse of that dynamic web application in few minutes.
After Thymeleaf.
We are going to spend a good amount of time understanding what is Spring boot, how it is different
from Spring MVC, Spring core, why everyone these days loving spring boot, whether they are going
to build a web applications or rest service or microservices.
Why everyone is adopting spring boot these days.
So all those kind of discussion we are going to do under the section of Spring Boot.
And once we are clear about the Spring Boot project, we are also going to discuss the concepts of spring
boot like auto configuration, how to build web application with the help of Spring Boot, Thymeleaf, Spring
MVC.
What is Spring Boot DevTools?
What is Spring Boot H2 database?
So all these are the beautiful concepts that are available inside the spring boot.
So we are going to spend a good amount of time understanding the spring boot, because Spring Boot is
a heart framework or project inside the spring ecosystem.
After spring boot, we are going to learn how to secure our web application or rest APIs with the help
of spring security framework available inside the spring ecosystem.
So with the help of spring security, we will learn how to implement authentication and authorization
role based access inside the web applications.
And along with that, we'll also learn how we.
Can leverage spring security to protect our Web application from the most common security vulnerabilities
like cross-site request forgery and cross-origin resource sharing.
After spring security, we will jump on to the projects and frameworks related to the persistent layer.
So inside the persistent layer, we are going to write a lot of Java code in order to interact with
the databases.
So that's where we will try to understand what is spring JDBC, how it is different from the core Java
JDBC, how the spring JDBC is going to make our lives easy with the help of JDBC templates available
inside the spring JDBC project.
After spring JDBC, we are going to discuss what is an ORM frameworks, how frameworks are better than
spring JDBC, how we can write a persistent code with the help of warm frameworks.
Why everyone is loving warm frameworks like Hibernate Spring Data, JPA these days.
So inside this course we are going to spend a good amount of time understanding all the warm framework
concepts and how to build a web applications with very less code of persistent logic where we don't
have to write a lot of SQL queries, we can rely completely on the ORM frameworks to perform some CRUD
operations onto the database and inside the spring data.
We'll also discuss about the advanced concepts like different mappings that we have inside ORM frameworks
like 1 to 1, one to many, many to one, many to many that are available inside Spring Data, JPA and
Hibernate.
And when we are discussing about spring data and spring Data JPA, we are going to build our web application
with the help of ORM framework like Spring Data JPA and internally this spring data JPA is going
to leverage Hibernate as an implementation framework.
So that's why we are going to discuss all the concepts that are common to the ORM frameworks like Spring
Data  JPA and Hibernate inside this course.
And once we are clear about these advanced concepts, we'll also discuss about how to sort the data,
how to do pagination and how to write queries with the help of JPQL format inside the web applications.
So all these advanced topics that are going to make our lives super easy as a developers.
So that's why I'm going to spend a good amount of time making you understanding about these advanced
concepts and advanced  ORM frameworks that we have inside the spring ecosystem.
And of course hibernate is a separate framework.
But as long as you are learning about spring data JPA and the concepts around the ORM frameworks,
both Spring Data JPA and Hibernate, they are going to work in a very similar manner.
Like I was telling before, whenever you are trying to build a web application with the help of Spring
Data JPA, internally your spring data JPA is going to leverage Hibernate framework as an implementation.
So that's why I want to highlight that we are not going to discuss spring data JPA and Hibernate separately.
We are going to discuss them as a common ORM framework.
Like if I'm explaining a concept like one to 1 or 1 to many that are applicable to ORM frameworks,
the same concept is applicable for both Spring data JPA and Hibernate.
And once we are clear about the spring data and spring Data JPA framework, we are also going to discuss
how to build the rest service and how to consume the rest service with the help of Spring Boot and the
concepts that we have inside the spring framework.
In the process, we will also learn how to secure our rest services.
And once we discuss all these main projects, we are also going to discuss the miscellaneous concepts
that we need to be aware whenever we are building web applications.
And one of the miscellaneous concepts that we are going to focus inside this course is logging.
So whenever we are discussing about logging, I'll be explaining you the importance of logging, what
are the different severities and how to control the severities of logging.
And in this process I'll explain you how Spring Boot is going to make our life so much easy in terms
of logging inside the web applications.
And we'll also discuss how to write our logs into a file that we have defined inside a folder location.
After logging, we will also discuss about how to define a property inside a property file and how to
read the properties that are available inside a property file from your Java code.
And once we are clear about these basic concepts of properties, we are also going to discuss advanced
concepts that is available inside the Spring boot, which is profiles.
So using profiles, I'll teach you how we can activate a specific set of properties or a logical group
of properties based upon the environment where your application is running.
And I'll also show you how to conditionally create the beans based upon the activated profile.
And once we are clear about these properties and profiles and at last we are going to discuss about
the spring boot actuator.
So we'll learn what is spring boot actuator, what are the different APIs or endpoints that are exposed
by the spring boot actuator and how we can leverage this information?
Available inside these APIs to understand the health of our web application and to monitor our web application
whenever we deploy our web application into a higher environment like production.
Once we discuss all the topics of Spring, Spring Boot and all other remaining framework towards the
end of the course, we are also going to deploy the Spring boot web application into the cloud environment.
And here I also want to highlight that I have put a lot of efforts in building the content of this course
so that you can easily understand all the concepts that we are going to discuss inside this course.
Like you can see here, this are all the sample content that I'm going to present.
So inside this content I have mentioned all the notes and sample code screenshots that you may need
whenever you want to brush up all these concepts in the future, even after one year or two years.
That way this content, you can always refer them whenever you have some questions or whenever you are
going for an interview.
You can always use this as a quick material to brush up your skills on the spring framework. And all
the complex topics inside the spring framework are presented in an easily understandable format.
So I'm going to share all this content in a PDF format to you.
That way you don't have to worry about taking notes.
You can simply focus on the course.
And apart from discussing about the theory inside this course, we are also going to implement a web
application by leveraging all the concepts that we are going to learn inside this course.
So let me show you the sample glimpse of the web application that we are going to build by the end of
this course.
Like you can see here, this is the sample web application that we are going to build.
So this web application is based upon the school functionality.
The reason why I have chose the school functionality is, school is a concept or a functionality which
is very close to our hearts and no one need a special knowledge to understand the functionality or the
logistics that we have around the school.
So that's why I have choose this school functionality.
And inside this school web application, we are going to build all the dynamic web pages with the help
of spring framework.
Like this is a home page and we'll also have many HTML form pages where we can enter the data inside
our web application.
And during this process, we'll also validate the data that is entered by my end user with the help
of validations concepts that are available inside the spring framework.
And apart from saving the data from the HTML forms, we'll also display the data from the back end onto
our easy School web application that we are going to build.
Like you can see here, all these all this information is coming from the back end database.
So with the help of Spring framework, I'll be showing how to load the data from the database and how
to send that to an UI web application and how to display that.
So all those kind of end to end concepts we are going to discuss.
And also we'll be having a login page and using this login page.
I'm going to secure my web application that way,
only authenticated and authorized users will access my web application.
So if I try to log in with my admin credentials, you can see there are many links that will be available
inside the dashboard where by clicking on these links my admin can see the data and he can perform many
actions on this web application.
So this way we are going to implement security inside our web application with the help of spring security
and we'll also implement role based access inside our web application and all the data that we are going
to save and fetch and display onto this web page will be handled with the help of frameworks like Spring
Data JPA, Spring JDBC and ORM frameworks that we are going to discuss inside this course.
I hope you are clear about what we are going to discuss inside this course.
So if you are looking to master the spring framework and its associated projects like Spring Boot, Spring
Data JPA, then definitely please go ahead and register to this course without any thought and I'm sure
that you will like this course based upon the content that we are going to discuss.
And like I said, I'm going to share the all the PDF content that I'm going to present inside this course.
And along with that, I'm also going to share you the source code of this web application, which I'm
maintaining inside a GitHub repository.
So with this I'm hoping you to see in the next lecture.
Thank you and bye.