I know you are super excited to start the journey of spring inside this course, but before we jump
on to the world of Spring framework, let me share a few important details that will help you to get
maximum benefits from this spring course.
The very first information that I want to share is, like you can see this is the GitHub repository
information where I'm maintaining all the source code related to this particular course.
And inside this source code you can see there are more than 50 example projects.
The reason why I'm giving so many example projects here is, I should have given a single project which
has all the source code that we are going to discuss inside this course, but that will be very tedious
job for you to understand everything with a single web application project, because inside this course
we are going to explore the features of the spring framework and we are going to build a web application
in a step by step manner.
So that's why to make your life easy, I have created a separate MAVEN project for each and every step
that we are going to take while building a web application or while discussing the spring related important
features.
And you can always understand what exactly we have implemented inside that particular example by looking
at the GitHub comments against that particular example project.
Like you can see here under example 4 project, we are going to implement primary annotation inside
our code, but before that I'll make sure I'm sharing enough details.
What is the purpose of primary annotation and how to write a sample code around that?
And all these examples, they are enhanced in a sequential manner, like whatever code that you see
inside example for the same code will be present inside the example 5 as well.
The only difference between example five and example four is, this example five will have more code related
to the feature of spring that we have discussed.
Like inside Example five.
I'll be showing you how to create a bean with the help of @Component annotation.
So this way all these examples, those are enhanced in a step by step manner and you can see we have
more than 50 projects and against each of these project I have mentioned what exactly we are going to
implement inside that particular example project.
So here I'm mentioning types of auto wiring and the purpose of qualifier annotation.
And here we are going to build an Hello World web app using Thymeleaf and DevTools demo.
And similarly, you can also look at this example 26, where I'll be providing an introduction to spring
security and how to configure spring security inside an web application.
So similarly, we have many other example projects, so that's why please travel along with me.
Like whenever I am creating a new web application, you don't have to create a new web application again.
Instead, you can keep updating the single web application that you have.
That way, it will be very easy for you to enhance your web application in a step by step manner.
But I'm giving so many examples of web applications just for your convenience, because using this example
projects, you can always compare,
what's the difference between example 34 and example 35.
That way you can identify the list of changes that I have made in order to achieve the functionality
that I'm highlighted here.
Like to migrate from JDBC template to spring data JPA.
So what I have done, what exactly I have done, you can always identify that by comparing the two example
projects like example 34 and example 35.
And the next important information that I want to share here is, I am going to discuss a lot of PowerPoint
slides like there are more than 200 PowerPoint slides.
So inside these slides I'll be discussing a lot of theory discussion.
I'll be having some screenshots, how to make certain code configurations.
What is the purpose of a particular annotation?
What is an internal flow architecture of a particular component inside spring framework?
So this PowerPoint slide I'm going to share as a PDF version to you.
So that way you don't have to take the notes while you are trying to understand the topic that I'm discussing.
So that's why don't worry about taking notes.
All the details that I'm going to discuss inside this course.
They are available inside the PDF file that I'm going to share inside this course.
So the same pdf file I have attached to this video.
So please go ahead and download the PDF and have that as a reference,
whenever you are looking at a particular lecture.
That way you can always try to correlate and you can also use the same pdf file to brush up the topics
that we have discussed inside this course, even after six months or even after one year.
And whenever you look at this PDF file, it will be very easy for you to understand or to grasp the
topics or to brush up the topics again.
And this will be a savior whenever you are trying to attend an interview on spring.
So in order
to download this PDF content, you can see under this lecture 2
there is an resources link and when you click on this resources link you will have an option to
download the file with the name spring.pdf.
So my request is,
please download this pdf.
Try to avoid taking notes.
Please completely concentrate on the course and of course if there is some unique approach that you
follow in taking notes, I would encourage you to continue that.
But please have this as a reference.
That way you are not trying to duplicate the effort or you are not trying to duplicate the information
in multiple places.
And the third important information that I want to share here is I have built this course by by assuming
you have zero knowledge on spring framework.
So due to that reason, I have provided a lot, many details at many places.
But for some reason, if you feel like you already know about a particular topic, you are free to skip
that particular lecture.
That way you won't feel get bored.
So that's why whenever you are trying to start a lecture first, try to understand if you already aware
of this particular concept that I'm going to discuss inside that lecture.
If yes, feel free to skip or you can fast forward very quickly that that way you also brush up the
concept very quickly while I'm discussing the same inside the lecture and inside this Section one and
Section two, I'm going to talk very detail about the spring framework.
What is the purpose of it?
Why should we use frameworks at all?
What are the spring core concepts?
That's why these first two courses are like entirely theory, but the actual coding implementations
will start from the section three, like, right, from how to create a bin inside the spring framework.
And from there we are going to build a web application with all the spring projects and with all
the features that we are going to discuss inside this course.
And the next information that I want to share is about the video quality and the pace of my communication.
For some reason, if you feel the quality of the video is not good, please make sure that you are going
to the settings option and make sure you are selecting at least 720P or 1080P option if it is available
because by default Udemy is going to change your quality of the video based upon your network speed.
So that's why always try to select an option of highest quality that you see inside the video.
That way the quality of the video will always stick to whatever quality that you have selected.
And at the same time, for some reason, if you feel like I'm talking too fast and I'm talking too slow,
Udemy also have an option of playback rate here.
If you feel like I'm talking too slow, you can go with an option of increasing the pace of my communication
like 1.25 x or 1.5 x based upon your comfort levels.
And if you feel like I'm talking too fast, then in that scenario you also have an option of slowing
my communication by taking an option of 0.75 x or 0.5 x.
So please try to select one of the option whatever comfortable for you because these are the universal
problems inside the Udemy.
Since inside the Udemy, the courses are going to be taken by students across the world.
Definitely there will be a gap in understanding the English language that we talk.
There will be a slang difference.
So that's why always feel free to select the playback rate that that is comfortable to you.
And throughout this course, at any point of time, if you have any question or if you stuck with any
issue, I will advise you to follow three steps.
The very first step is first, try to Google for the issue that you are facing, like take help from
the Google and StackOverflow and the developer community that we have that way.
In the process, you will also learn how to look for the solutions that you face inside the real world
projects.
And even after looking the information inside the Google and StackOverflow, you are not able to resolve
the issue.
Then look at the Q&A section of this course where many students might have posted many questions.
And if you look at those questions and answers that I'm mentioning, you can try to correlate if that
issue is related to you, if not as a last step, you can always post the question that you have to
me through the Q&A section that we have here, or if you feel like you want to send a personal message
to me, you can always send a message to me inside Udemy and it will directly come to my Udemy inbox
and I'll try to respond to you as soon as possible.
And at last I also want to highlight you that Udemy will ask you for your review at an early stage of
the course, and if you feel like you are not yet ready to provide a review, feel free to skip the
review process.
And I would always advise you to watch at least 30% of the lectures inside the course and that way you
will be in a good.
Positioned to provide a review to the course.
So with this, I'm super excited to start the journey of the spring along with you.
Thank you and I'll see you in the next lecture bye.