Let's start our discussion by having a brief introduction about what is a spring framework.
That way you have some basic understanding.
What is spring and why we have to learn and why everyone in the software industry, especially inside
the Java ecosystem, is using spring to a great extent.
So if you really ask me what is a spring, the spring framework, which we can shortly refer it as a
spring, is a mature, powerful and highly flexible Java framework focused on building web applications
inside Java ecosystem.
The reason why I'm saying it's a mature and powerful framework is, it is not something which got introduced
recently.
Spring Framework initially introduced around two decades back, which is in the year of 2002.
From 2002, spring evolved a lot based upon the market trends and based upon the developer needs inside
Java ecosystem.
That's why we can confidently call Spring Framework is a matured and powerful and flexible framework
to build Java web applications.
So what makes Spring Framework as a favorite framework for all the Java developers is it will make developer
life easy by allowing quicker and easier ways to build web applications, focusing on speed, simplicity
and productivity, which are all contributed to make Spring as a world most popular Java framework.
On a day to day basis, we as a developers have to focus a lot on business logic.
So considering that as a developer, I should not put lot of efforts in doing configurations, in writing
some dependencies that my application is needed, I should be free from all those requirements.
The reason is, as a developer and as a human being, I should focus on the business logic and I should
have some easier mechanisms to support all the requirements that I need for a Java Web applications
in the form of defining dependencies, writing configurations.
So all these supporting components is provided by spring in a quicker and easier manner.
We will discuss in the coming lectures.
For now, please make a note that spring makes your programming of Java web applications quicker and
easier, and the scenario can be anything whether you might be building a web application or reactive
application or even a microservices or a backend for a mobile application or you want to build a
complex application which will stream data over your enterprise.
So for all these kind of scenarios, Spring has supporting tools that can help during development.
And spring is born as an alternative to the EJBs that are very famous in the early 2000.
So we all know Enterprise Java Beans, which is invented as part of Java Enterprise Edition, is
very complex in nature.
So if you ask any of your colleagues who worked on Ejbs around 2000, they can clearly tell you that,
EJB is a super  complicated framework to build web applications.
So to avoid all those complications and to make developer life easy, spring came as an alternative
to the EJBs framework, and within no time spring overtook all its opponents.
Just because it is very simple to build web applications and it has variety of features and third party
library integrations that we can see in the coming lectures.
So with all these features that spring provides, it overtook all its opponents like Ejbs, struts.
So all these frameworks are now behind the spring and spring is majorly being used over the Java ecosystem,
and it is so popular that its main competitor, which is Oracle Java Enterprise Edition, they quit
their race and they hand over that enterprise edition to the community after Java Enterprise Edition
eight to version just because everyone started and continued to use Spring as their favorite Java framework.
And that's why Oracle felt that there is no meaning putting efforts building Enterprise Edition in competing
spring framework.
With all these reasons and their own business reasons, Oracle handover that enterprise edition maintenance
to a community.
And that's why the recent versions of Enterprise Edition we should call Jakarta Enterprise Edition,
but not Java Enterprise Edition, because Oracle owns the brand name of Java.
So due to that reason, they renamed that Java Enterprise edition to Jakarta Enterprise Edition.
So Jakarta Enterprise Edition maintains by a community of developers.
So you can ask me what is the main reason that Spring framework is so successful?
I would say the very first and main reason is.
It evolves over the period based upon the market trends, like in the initial days.
Spring came up with only spring core and spring MVC pattern to build monolithic applications.
Later on when industry is moving towards a microservices cloud native applications.
Then spring also started evolving by introducing lot of features like Spring Boot, which will make
developer life very easy in building web applications, microservices applications.
So with the reasons that it evolves on day to day basis and it's very simple to use and it will make
developer life easy.
Spring became one of the most popular Java framework On top of that, Spring is not a commercial framework.
It's an open source.
Anyone can use this spring framework without paying any money.
So who don't want the open source framework that is providing all the production ready enterprise features?
That's why industry adopted this spring framework in a very fast manner and due to this reason over
the last few decades, Spring has a large and active community of developers who continuously give feedback
to the spring team and they also provide help to other developers or StackOverflow or writing many blogs
over the web.
That way, if any developer struck due to any issues, they can always reach out to these active community
and get help immediately.
You can also see how popular the spring framework is inside Java ecosystem.
So in 2021, when J Rebel team, they did a survey with all the Java developers with a question that
what is the framework that you use inside your projects on day to day basis, you can see 62% of the
developers said they are using Spring boot or spring related frameworks, followed by Dropwizard, Quarkus,
Micronaut, Vertex and other is 17%.
So inside others we may have many other frameworks, but you can see spring is a clearly a winner here.
And similarly, one more survey that is done by snic.io website here.
They went ahead and asked all the Java developers to provide what are the frameworks that they use and
they can select more than one response.
That's why you can see the sum of all these percentages not matching with 100%.
The reason is the developers can select more than one response, but still you can see Spring Boot has
50%, Spring MVC has 31%.
So with this, please be super confident that you are learning a hot and trending Java framework, which
is spring and as and when we discuss about it features in the coming lectures, I'm definitely confident
that you will also start liking the spring framework with this.
I'm hoping you got a brief introduction of what is spring, but don't worry if any of the statements
that I made is not clear to you.
The reason is we will discuss each and every feature of spring in the coming lectures in detail.
And when we start discussing all those features, I'm sure you will also like and agree with my statements
that spring is a most popular Java framework.
Thank you and I'll see you in the next lecture bye.